

# **Anil Kumar**

### JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

## CAREER OVERVIEW

I am a professional UI developer, Having 3 years of technical experience in IT. Proficient in developing Single Page Apps using React Ecosystem. As developer worked in all phases of project life cycles. Strong learning curve in adapting quickly to emerging technologies.

## AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- React & React native Libraries
- Angular Framework
- JavaScript, TypeScript
- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Grommet
- Redux, Redux-Saga
- RxJS, Axios HTTP Libraries
- · Docker, REST APIs, Zipkin
- MySQL, Oracle 10g
- Oracle EBS
- StackBlitz, FireBase
- Github, Tortoise SVN version control
- Oops concept, ES6, Pl/Sql

#### HOBBIES

- Playing & watching Cricket
- · Reading blogs & Quora
- Participate in hackathons
- Exploring new destinations

## CONTACT

+91 - 9672598162 anilpandiya05@gmail.com anilpandiya.github.io linkedin.com/in/anilpandiya github.com/anilpandiya codepen.io/anilpandiya

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

iBASEt Ahmedabad

Apr 2019 - present

Project: Solumina MES web app, Unit info mobile app

Client: Lockheed Martin, Air Bus

Responsibilites:

- Participated at various stages of web application developments.
- Application is being developed using React ecosystem and used Rest APIs as backend architecture to access the Mongo database.
- Building reusable components for future use and worked on maintaining versions & publishing packages.
- Contributed in Defect Fixing, Performance Tuning and Deployment Process well.

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Capgemini Bangalore

2017 - Apr 2019

**Project: Global Time Entry System** 

Client: Sogeti High Tech (France & Mexico)

Responsibilites:

- Participated at various stages of web application enhancements.
- Application is being developed using Angular 6 framework and used Rest APIs as backend architecture to access the Oracle database.
- Developed many CR's as well for different regions based on specific requirements and worked on maintaining versions.
- Contributed in post-production activities such as Defect Fixing, Performance Tuning and Framework Upgradation.

#### **INTERN**

IBM Software COE Jaipur

2016 - 2017

Responsibilities:

- Contributed on existing application Security Management System's enhancements.
- Planned new designs and functionality and developed modules.
- Prepared MD50 and knowledge management documents.

## ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

## **BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY**

Rajasthan Technical University 2013 - 2017

- Graduated with Honors 74.03% in Computer Science & Engineering stream

#### SECONDARY & SENIOR SEC EDUCATION

Rajasthan Board of Secondary Education

- Completed 12th class with 70.6% and 10th class with 88%